

# Chaitanya Giri

**Backend Lead** 

My Contact

me@chaitanyagiri.in

+91-9424108852

Chaitanyagiri

contact.chaitanyagiri.in

#### **Tech Skills**

- Python (DRF, Django, Flask)
- Javascript (NodeJs, React, NextJs etc.)
- MongoDB, Elastic-search, Postgres
- Docker for containerising, Git for version control

# **Education Background**

- The LNM Institute of Information technology Bachelors in Computer and Communications Engineering Completed in 2020
- Senior Secondary School Sector 10, Bhilai Physics, Chemistry, Maths with Computer Science as optional Completed in 2015

#### **About Me**

With 3+ years of backend development experience, I have delivered more than 5 different products to production, Wherever I work I make sure I have an impact in the team and it's overall performance. Over the course of time I have taken up responsibilities as a leader in teams, thus helping them create impactful processes to follow, my way of inspiring/impressing people is by getting things done and showing how to do it which basically means I love to code.

## **Hands On Experience**

- In system design and microservices best suited for the organisation.
- In designing integration and deployment pipelines best suited for the team.
- In creating and maintaining all backend infrastructure on AWS.
- In building custom SAAS(s) for US healthcare.
- In research and implementation of multitenant systems to achieve scale.

# **Professional Experience**

Demons PTE LTD | Backend Lead Jan 2022 - Present

- Key Skills: Javascript(Nodejs, express, nextjs), MongoDB, Redis (for queuing), AWS (ECR, ECS, ELB, EC2, Route53), github actions, git, docker, web3js etc.
- Integrated smart contract deployed on blockchains like Ethereum and Zilliqa.
- Designed and developed entire backend distributed system consisting of 4 different microservices readily interacting with each other to deliver a seamless experience to UI while giving us the capability to scale individual services as we wish.
- Designed and developed entire CICD pipeline which deploys the above mentioned services to AWS with the capability to have multiple development and production environments.
- Integrated multiple smart contracts for demons.world one
  of which allowed people to stake their tokens people used
  the platform I built to stake more than 500K USD worth of
  our tokens.

# Chaitanya Giri

**Backend Lead** 

## **Professional Experience**

Innovaccer Analytics | SDE Jan 2020 - Dec 2021

- Key Skills: CI/CD, Multi-Tenancy, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Data Modelling, System Design, Microservices
- Most of my work in Innovaccer revolved around products targeting care and referral management solutions. I helped the team build 2 products from scratch namely: Strategy and Contact Center which were eventually sold to multiple clients during my tenure. I developed and maintained the two product's backend service during my tenure. Apart from these products I also worked with products namely InCare, CRW and InOffice for a brief period of time. I was involved in solving the engineering challenges that we faced as we scaled up and onboarded new clients, for the two products mentioned above I streamlined the CICD pipelines and worked on Multi-tenancy, System Architecture, Worked with multiple cloud services efficiently by vendors like AWS, Other notable mention of my work would be collaborating with multiple teams and people within the company to achieve what we call Phase 1/2 for multi-tenancy. Onboarded and integrated the two backend services so that they were able to communicate with multi-tenant services. Part of my work also involved communicating with clients so that we can cater to their requirements and providing them the resolution to their queries.

#### Innovaccer Analytics | Summer Intern May 2019 – July 2019

- Key skills: Python, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Docker, GIT
- Built a custom dockerized solution which enabled the developer to set up the complete testing environment and
  insert randomised mock seed data to appropriate places which allowed the developer to test the code in a
  production-like environment without worrying about integration issues of live sensitive US healthcare data and
  comply to HIPPA.
- Learnt about US healthcare and how technology can help solve a lot of issues in it.

#### **Achievements**

July 2022- Present	Wrote more than 1 Lakh line of code to build distributed system to handle entire backend <b>compliant with https://12factor.net/</b> for a new project.
Early 2022	Built and integrated entire backend for a staking portal which accumulated more than 1.3 Million Tokens(~500K USD at the time of writing this)
2020 - 2021	Won Quarterly awards for leading a team and delivering entire backend for a product called Contact Center. (Innovaccer Analytics)